

Associate seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software Development, Application Development, Application Design, Project Management, Change Management, Requirement Analysis, Informatica, Unit Testing, SQL Server, SOAP UI, COBOL, Oracle, CICS, VSAM, JIRA, DB2, JCL



Current Designation: Associate Total Experience: 10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Highest Degree: PG Diploma [Business Management] Current Company: Cognizant

Current Location: Kolkata

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Pune, Kolkata Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: Associate, Software Developer, Software Engineering, Software Development, Application

Development, Application Design, Project Management, Change Management, Requirement Analysis, Informatica, Unit

Testing, SQL Server, SOAP UI, COBOL, Oracle, CICS, VSAM, JIRA, DB2

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Overall 9.11 years of IT experience with expertise in Data management, Oracle, Informatica, Mainframe development in domain banking & financial solutions.

Worked on various projects for Euroclear, Credit Suisse AG in Banking and Financial Services and Wells Fargo from offshore as well as onsite location. Played key role in Requirements Analysis, Design, Development and Testing of Application Software. Strong business knowledge in BFS domain with L0 certification.

Expertise includes Oracle, DB2, PL/SQL, Informatica, SSIS, SQL Server, Python , PL/1, JCL, VSAM, DB2, SoapUi, GIT. Onsite experience in Credit Suisse AG, Zurich, Switzerland. Have efficiently and effectively managed critical deliverables, single handedly with excellent communication and client-handling skills.

Currently working as a team lead. Thus, responsibility is not only confined to management related work but also core development and review as a senior developer.

Work Experience

Cognizant as Associate Nov 2010 to Till Date

Relevant Project Experience

Wells Fargo Bank

Project Name BDW-Oracle Exadata-WFAT Migration

Duration

Location December 2016 - Present

Kolkata, India

Technology PL/SQL, Oracle, Informatica, SSIS, SQL Server, UNIX

Project Abstract Wells Fargo advisors use this tool to analyse the data. This tool is used to get data from SQL server. This is a rewrite project, after migrating some data from sql server to oracle. Wells Fargo Advisors use this data to advice the clients and propose the best plan for investment to their clients.

Role

Responsibilities Team Lead

- Gap Analysis, creating design documents, program specifications, mapping documents, Requirement Analysis
- project estimation, project plan, delivery metrics
- Analysis of the existing functionality
- Designing program specification
- Design of various individual modules
- Coding of the modules
- Helping team members with their assignments
- Unit and integration testing
- Resolving SIT/PTA issues
- Implementing end to end critical application features

Credit Suisse AG. Zurich. Switzerland

Project Name Tax functionality shift

Duration

Location December 2014 - November 2016

Kolkata, India

Technology PL/1, DB2, JCL, Webservice, IMS, SoapUI, Rexx

Project Abstract A lot of tax functionalities have been implemented in Asset servicing application. This is an architectural and strategic issue, so the proposed new application for tax recalculation is to extract all tax functionality out of CAIR application to establish standalone solution that can be easily transferred to tax area.

Role

Responsibilities Developer

- Requirement Analysis
- Analysis of the existing functionality
- Designing program specification
- Design of various individual modules
- Coding of the modules
- Helping team members with their assignments
- Unit and integration testing
- Resolving SIT/PTA issues
- Implementing end to end critical application features

Project Name Corba to Web Service Migration

Duration

Location September 2012 - November 2014

Kolkata, India

Technology PL/1, DB2, JCL, Webservice, IMS, SoapUI, Rexx

Project Abstract Credit Suisse currently has a support contract with Progress Software which is due to expire by end of year 2014. With a dwindling number of companies supporting CORBA, its parent company has not invested in future development of the product. CORBA has reached near end of life with shrinking market share and increased risk of staying on ORBIX in mainframe. Given the background, Credit Suisse has planned to migrate from CORBA to a crossdivisional, cross-platform synchronous communication technology and has opted for web-service technology (SOAP/https) using top-down, or WSDL-first approach. As a prerequisite, this migration required enhancements in IMS to provide web services support in mainframe. Credit Suisse has defined three major work streams for the entire CORBA to Web Services migration and has solicited responses for the migration program execution.

Role

Responsibilities Developer

- Requirement Analysis
- Designing the new web service using IFMS
- Consumer migration from Corba services to Web Service
- Communicating with onsite coordinator/Interface owner/ consumer migration team when required
- Design and coding review of various web services
- Helping team members with their assignments
- Unit testing
- Defect management and fixing
- Resolving PTA/ production issues
- End to end responsibility for migration of various applications involving analysis, migration, testing and test log creation
- Consumer Support Provided support to web service consumers

Euroclear Bank

Project Name Complexity Reduction

Duration

Location June 2012 - July 2012

Kolkata, India

Technology PL/1, DB2, JCL, Rexx

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from DR.B.C.ROY ENGINEERING COLLEGE, DURGAPUR in 2010

PG: PG Diploma (Business Management) from Narsee Monjee, Mumbai in 2014

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Informatica, SSIS, COBOL, CICS, JCL,	
PL/SQL, Python, Oracle, DB2	
SQL Server, VSAM, IMS, CORBA	
Windows 98/XP/2000, MVS OS	
corba tester, JIRA	
XPEDITOR, Soap UI	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				
Bengali				

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time